Class of 1897 Records, 1893-1967
Smith College Archives
Class of 1897 Records
1893-1967
Smith College. Class of 1897.
RG 80 UUID:4136fcd3-a792-4468-a8ab-e1d1b7f43fad
35 boxes (20.3 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection is in 35 boxes and contains photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, letters, and other memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1897, as well as individual student files.
The Class of 1897 was the nineteenth entering class and the nineteenth graduating class of Smith College.
The Class of 1897 records, 1893-1967, contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1897, including materials from commencement, reunions, senior dramatics, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, letters, and other memorabilia.
Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, scrap books and class notes.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1897 records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Baccalaureate Service 1897 (Box 1525, Folder 1)
- Collation and Alumnae Tea 1897 (Box 1525, Folder 2)
- Commencement 1897 (Box 1525, Folder 3)
- Commencement: Photos 1897 (Box 1525, Folder 4)
- Commencement: Music 1897 (Box 1525, Folder 5)
- Class History 1893-1920's (Box 1525, Folder 6)
- Freshman Grind by Class of 1896 undated (Box 1525, Folder 7)
- Groups 1893-1897 (Box 1525, Folder 8)
- Groups 1893-1897 (Box 1525, Folder 9)
- Ivy Day 1897 (Box 1525, Folder 10)
- Ivy Day: Photos 1897 (Box 1525, Folder 11)
- Junior Prom 1896 (Box 1525, Folder 12)
- Junior Reception given by Class of 1898 1896 (Box 1525, Folder 13)
- Junior Ushers 1896 (Box 1525, Folder 14)
- Class Secretary's Correspondence 1957-1963 (Box 1526, Folder 1)
- Photographs: Groups 1895 (Box 1526, Folder 2)
- Class Letters 1919-1967 (Box 1526, Folder 3)
- Pins 1907 (Box 1526, Folder 4)
- Secretary's Report 1893-1913 (Box 1526, Folder 5)
- Songs 1893-1897 (Box 1526, Folder 6)
- Sophomore Receptions 1893 (Box 1526, Folder 7)
- Sophomore-Senior Reception for 1895 1895 (Box 1526, Folder 8)
- Student Rooms undated (Box 1526, Folder 9)
- Class Supper 1897 (Box 1526, Folder 10)
- Treasurer's Report 1895-1958 (Box 1526, Folder 11)
- Unidentified undated (Box 1526, Folder 12)
- "Weep" 1894 (Box 1526, Folder 13)
- Reunions 1912-1962 (Box 1527, Folder 1)
- Reunion Bulletin 1918-1927 (Box 1527, Folder 2)
- Reunion 1898 (Box 1527, Folder 3)
- Reunion 190 (Box 1527, Folder 4)
- Reunion 1907-1910 (Box 1527, Folder 5)
- Reunion 1907 (Box 1527, Folder 6)
- Reunion 1912 (Box 1527, Folder 7)
- Reunion 1917 (Box 1527, Folder 8)
- Reunion 1922 (Box 1527, Folder 9)
- Reunion 1932 (Box 1528, Folder 1)
- Reunion 1937 (Box 1528, Folder 2)
- Reunion 1942 (Box 1528, Folder 3)
- Reunion 1947 (Box 1528, Folder 4)
- Reunion 1950 (Box 1528, Folder 5)
- Reunion 1952 (Box 1528, Folder 6)
- Reunion 1957 (Box 1528, Folder 7)
- Reunion 1962-1967 (Box 1528, Folder 8)
- Reunion Memorabilia undated (Box 1528, Folder 9)
- Reunion Songs undated (Box 1528, Folder 10)
- Senior Dramatics: The Merchant of Venice (Box 1529, Folder 1)
- Senior Dramatics 1897 (Box 1529, Folder 2)
- Senior Dramatics- Photographs 1897 (Box 1529, Folder 3)
- Senior Dramatics- Photographs 1897 (Box 1529, Folder 4)
- Senior Dramatics- Photographs 1897 (Box 1529, Folder 5)
- Senior Dramatics- Photographs 1897 (Box 1529, Folder 6)
- Senior Dramatics: Prompt Book 1897 (Box 1529.1, Folder 1)
- Senior Dramatics: Prompt Book and Clippings 1897 (Box 1529.1, Folder 2)
- Senior Dramatics: Stage Properties Book 1897 (Box 1529.1, Folder 3)
- Memorabilia (Box OV)